Guide to the Clarke Family Papers, 1904-1968 M0292
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Clarke Family Papers
1904-1968
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Clarke family
M0292
10 Linear Feet ca. 10 linear ft.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, photographs (of China), books and pamphlets about Chinese art, etc.
Biographical Note
The daughter of Dr. Charles Fletcher Johnson and Agnes Elliott Johnson, Ruth Clarke was born on April 2, 1890 in Wei Hsien, Shantung, China where she quickly mastered Mandarin Chinese. She was educated at Miss Jewell's School in Shanghai which was also attended by Miss Pearl Buck. After visiting her Uncle Hosmer Johnson in Washington D.C., Ruth entered and graduated from Wilson College (Chambersburg, Pa.) in 1912. She then returned to Shanghai to accept a teaching position at Miss Jewell's.
In 1916 Ruth Johnson accepted a new position in the Peking American School. It was there that she met J. Eric G. Clarke whom she married on June 21, 1916 in Tsinanfu, Shantung. The Rev. W. P. Chalfant officiated. Kathleen Clarke, Margaret Emma Johnson, Gerald Clarke and Hosmer F. Johnson were members of the wedding party Dating from this ceremony, the couple often signed their combined correspondence Rutheric. Following a brief honeymoon in Tai Shan, the couple returned to Peking where they resided for the next 16 years. During this period Mrs. Clarke made several trips to the United States where she exhibited many of the fabulous Oriental art treasures she had collected throughout her stay in China.
Soon after the couple moved to Shanghai the threat of war between Japan and China became reality. Overnight, internment camps were set up for aliens like the Clarkes. Their homes were occupied by Japanese soldiers as soon as they were evacuated by the local Occupation authorities. From April 10, 1943 until a few weeks following the Japanese surrender to MacArthur on August 14, 1945, the Clarkes were confined at Lung Hwa Camp near Peking.
Among the nearly 1800 interns at Lung Hwa were men and women from all professions and backgrounds. Although spirits were high during the first season at the camp, morale worsened during the winter--food became scarce and poorer in quality and the stoves which the Japanese installed on each floor of the ten dormitories were never lit. The cubicles they occupied were 4`8 by 22' long. Despite the difficult conditions they encountered at the camp, the Clarkes and their fellow inmates managed to maintain a high level of personal development which is reflected in the many activities enjoyed at the camp: lectures, plays, musical productions and many other kinds of intellectual stimulation. One of the most amusing highlights of their stay was the development of a game called Dictionary Please. Because of their limited reading material, the Clarkes designed a game which relied only upon the dictionary they brought with them and their active imaginations. The game was so successful that it became a partial livelihood following their return to America in 1946.
Residing in Portland, Oregon, Mr. and Mrs. Clarke remained active socially and intellectually. Mrs. Clarke served as president of Zonta International and the Lewis and Clarke's Women's League. Mrs. Clarke now resides in Mountain View, California.
Provenance
Gift of Ruth Elliott Johnson Clarke.
Access Restrictions
None.
Reference Materials
1. Palmer, J.P.: Jade Spring Books; London, 1967.
2. The Encyclopedia Sinica Couling, Samuel Kelly & Walsh; Shanghai, 1917.
3. Thiel, albert W.R.: Chinese Pottery and Stoneware Thos. nelson & Sons; N.Y., N.D.
4. Goette, John: Jade Lore Kelly & Walsh; Shanghai, 1936.
5. Forsyth, Robb. Coventry: Shanting, The Sacred Province of China Christian Literature Society; Shanghai, 1912
6. Graham, Dorothy: Through the moon Door J. H. Sears & Co.; N.Y., 1926.
7. Brandt, J.: Introduction to Literary Chinese North China Union Language School; Peking, 1927.
8. Weale, B.L. Putnam: The Vanished Empire Macmillan & Co.; London, 1926.
9. Jennu, Delia: Letter from Peking Oxford UP; London, 1967.
10. Busheel, Stephen W.: Chinese [UNK] V. I Eyre & Spottiswoode; London, 1909.
11. Smith, Arthur H.: Chinese Characteristics 3rd ed. Fleming H. Revell Co.; n.y., 1894.
12. Grubb, Norman P.: C.T.Studd, Cricketer & Pioneer Religious Tract Society; London, 1933.
13. Martin, W.A.P.: The Siege in Peking Oliphant Anderson & Ferrier; Edinburgh, 1900.
14. Lymn, Jermyn Chi-Hung: Social Life of The Chinese in Peking China Booksellers; Peking, 1928.
15. Strong, [UNK] [UNK]: a Sketch of Chinese Cuts & Crafts China Bhsellers; Peking, 1926.
Clarke family
- Ruth Johnson Clarke Correspondence-, 1904- (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General note
  originals
  - Juliet J. to Mamma and Papa from Shanghai, 2-6-04; Item 1.
  - R. J. To Papa and Mamma and Hosner from Shanghai, 2-13-04; Item 2.
  - J. Montague to Mama from Shanghai, 3-12-04; Item 3.
  - Juliet Montague to Mama from Shanghai, 4-15-04; Item 4.
  - [R.J.] to Mama and Hosner from Shanghai (fragment burned), 4-27-04; Item 5.
  - R.J. to Mama, Papa, and brothers from Shanghai, 5-20-04; Item 6.
  - R.J. to Mama from Shanghai, 6-2-04; Item 7.
  - R.J. to Mama from Shanghai, 6-4-04; Item 8.
  - R.J. To Mama, Papa Hosner from Shanghai, 6-17-04; Item 9.
  - R.J. to Mamma, Hosner from Shanghai from Shanghai [2-04], undated; Item 10.
  - R.J. to Mama and Papa from Shanghai [3/4-04], undated; Item 11.
- Ruth Johnson Clarke Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ruthie to Mrs. C.F. Johnson note- invitation to tea, undated; Item 1.
  - R.J. to Papa [from Shanghai], 1904; Item 2.
  - R.J. to Daddy [from W.D.C.], 12-28-08; Item 3.
  - R.J. to Daddy [from W.D.C.], 7-16-11; Item 4.
  - R.J. to Daddy [fr. Chamersburg], 9-1911; Item 5.
  - R.J. to Daddy [fr. Chambersburg], 10-1-11; Item 6.
  - R.J. to Daddy [fr. Chambersburg], 11-1911; Item 7.
  - R.J. to Daddy [fr. Chambersburg] m. revolutionist and Manchu trouble, 3-3-[1912]; Item 8.
  - R.J. to Mother and Dad [fr. Shanghai] re: Hosner's operation and R.J.'s illness, etc., 2-28-15; Item 9.
  - R.J. to Family [fr. Shanghai] re: possible teaching position in Peking, 3-8-15; Item 10.
  - R.J. to Family [fr. Shanghai], 5-10-15; Item 11.
  - RJ to EGC, 1-22-16; Item 12.
  - RJ to EGC, 9-3-16; Item 13.
  - RJ to EGC, 10-3-16; Item 14.
  - wedding announcement, 6-16; Item 15.
  - Rutheric to Daddy, Mummy, Hosner [fr. Peking], 1-1-17; Item 16.
  - RJC to Daddy, 1916; Item 17.
  - Sunday noon. R, Eric & Frank to Dearest Ones RMS Empress of Russia to Japan, undated; Item 18.
  - RJC to Eric [fr. Tsinan], 9-23-20; Item 19.
  - Ruth and Eric to Family [fr. Shanghai], 4-30-21; Item 20.
  - RJC to Family, Yokohama RMS Emperor of Russia [to Vancouver], 5-6-21; Item 21.
  - RJC to Family Kobe m. Sir Reg. and Lady Gamble, Mr. Cruikshank, 5-5-[21]; Item 22.
  - RJC to Family, Nagasaki RMS Empress of Russia m. Dr. and Mrs. Packard of the Rockefeller in Peking, 5-13-21; Item 23.
  - [RJC] to Uncles Hosner, Frank, and Milton Delaware Gap, Pa. m. Eric's illness, 7-24-21; Item 24.
  - RJC to family Easton, Pa., 7-31-21; Item 25.
  - RJC to Eric, Tsinanfu, m. Mother and Kathleen in Tientsin, 1-29-22; Item 26.
  - RJC to Family m. New York trip and exhibit Arden studies and Dr. Slean, 4-13-29; Item 27.
  - RJC to Daddy [Wilmington, Delaware], 4-30-31; Item 28.
  - RJC to EGC, USS President Jackson, photo & note, 12-13-33; Item 29.
  - RJC to Mrs. SS Corbett [NY] re: Mother's funeral, 11-1-36; Item 30.
  - RJC to Scott S. Corbett, 11-1-36; Item 31.
  - RJC to Mrs. SS Corbett, [11-1-36]; Item 32.
  - RJC to Friends [Shanghai] good letter concerning uncertain political state in China (Shanghai) in 1937. Incident Friday 13, 1937. m. George Scranton; Dr. Bob Reischauer's death; bombing of Japanese consulate; typhoon, Item 33.
  - RJC to Eric N.L., undated Wednesday; Item 34.
  - RJC to Daddy and Mother, undated May 4; Item 35.
  - RJC to Lori Treece [U.S.], 5-8-48; Item 36.; (copy)
  - RJC to Margaret Hager's Mother, Portland Oregon, 1-28-49; Item 37.
- RJC To Beth Rogerson. in original order-not listed individually, 1929-31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Eric G. Clarke Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EGC to Miss Johnson Peking ALS, 4-10-15; Item Item 1.
  - Papa Clarke to Ruth Peking re: engagement of son to Ruth ALS & CU (enclosuree), 1-22-16; Item 2.
  - [EGC to Ruth] [Peking] (personal) AL, 2-2-16; Item 3.
  - EGC to Ruth [Peking] (personal) & cover. ALS, 2-22-16; Item 4.
  - Enclosure to #4, sketch of ring design for wedding, Item 5.
  - EGC [to Ruth] [Peking] (personal) & cover, 2-26-16; Item 6.
  - EGC [to Ruth] & cover [Peking] (note enclosed) ALS, 2-3-16; Item 7.
  - EGC [to Ruth] & cover ALS [Peking], 3-3-16; Item 8.
  - Enclosure to #8 S.E. Luca [?] to EGC. Peking, 3-3-16; Item 9.
  - EGC [to Ruth] [Peking], undated; Item 10.
  - Coded telegram & cover [EGC to RJC] Peking, 3-29-16; Item 11.
  - EGC to Ruth and cover ALS, 3-5-16; Item 12.
  - Enclosure to #12 Hadleys to Ruth ANS, Item 13.
    - [5-16] Next month EGC to little Scampykins Peking ALS and cover, Item 13A.
  - EGC [to Ruth] and cover, [5-21-16]; Item 14.
  - [6-16] EGC [to Ruth] ALS, Item 15.
  - [EGC to Ruth] AN, [1916]; Item 16.
  - ALS and cover, [1916]; Item 17.
  - ANS and cover, 7-27-16; Item 18.
  - Rutheric to Dad, Mother, and Hosmer ALS [Peking], 8-20-16; Item 19.
  - Rutheric to Dad and Mummy Peking (TL & ALS combined), 3-11-17; Item 20.
  - Enclosure to #20 Sunday 4 PM AL fragment [Ruth] to Daddy, Mummy & Hozziekins, (no date); Item 21.
  - EGC to Mother and Dad [Peking] ALS, 9-29-20; Item 22.
  - copy telegram DT Tsinan, 4-24-21; Item 23.
  - TLS EGC to Dad, 5-18-22; Item 24.
  - ALS EGC [to Ruth] Peking, 11-5-27; Item 25.
  - ALS EGC [to Ruth], 11-11-27; Item 26.
  - TLS EGC to Ruthie & Margaret et al. Shanghai re: CFJ's death, 5-19-31; Item Item 27.
  - Enclsure to #27, funeral address by Rev. R.A. Torrey, Jr. CFJ, M.D. DT, Item 28.
  - Enclosure to #27, funeral address by L.J. Davies Dr. CFJ in Relation to the Shantung Mission and Tsinan Station DT, Item 29.
  - Enclosure to #27 RJC tp Family ALS carbon, Item 30.
  - EGC to Mummy [Ruth] ALS, 6-21-31; Item 31.
  - EGC to Ruth Margaret and Bess, 11-2-36; Item 32.
  - [EGC] tp Ruth re: Mother Johnson's death AL fragment, undated-Mon 9 Nov 1931?; Item 33.
  - EGC to Daddy, Mummy, & Margo ALS, undated-Apr 26 1916?; Item 34.
  - EGC to Ruth ALS [during Japanese trip], 6-25-[21]; Item 35.
  - EGC to Dad TLS Peking m. unrest if Wu Pei Fu think things are going right., Aug 15 [?] [1916]; Item 36.
  - cover [EGC] to Ruth, April 2, 1961; Item 37.
- Hosner Johnson Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ALS and cover HJ [to RJC] m. Mother Clarke's & Dad Johnson's death, wedding plans w/Cora. Wei Hsin, Shantung, 10-25-16; Item Item 1.
  - Hosmer to Father and Mother TL carbon (Hong Kong) m. Queen Victoria, account of journey, 1-13-28; Item 2.
  - (Singapore, actually written 1-17) TL journey, 2-12-28; Item 3.
  - (Sumatra) (1-24) TL journey, 2-14-28; Item 4.
  - HJ to Folks (Tsinan) parents wedding anniversary TLS, 3-28-29; Item 5.
  - HJ to Mother ALS [Chefoo?], 10-14-34; Item 6.
  - HJ to Mother TLS (New York), 2-14-35; Item 7.
  - fragment ALS m. Hector [Elizabeth], 1934; Item 8.
  - HJ to Mother TLS (NY) M. Nanking murder, Hector [Elizabeth], 11-17-? [probably '34]; Item 9.
  - HJ to Ruth. postcard AS [China?] re: Elizabeth's birth that a.m. [Charles, Eric, other kid], 11-21-40; Item 10.
- Series B (Box 5)
  - 1. A-B
  - 2. Accident Claims (Taxi-NY)
  - 3. Business License Reports
  - 4. Centilli
  - 5. Chao-Ch'un Teh
  - 6. John Crawforal
  - 7. Customs-Import License
  - 8. Data on Cupids + Paintings
  - 9. Evans, Ruby
  - 10. E
  - 11. Incoming Corr. E-G
  - 12. Far Easterner
  - 13. Faris, Paul + Helena
  - 14. Farm (John I. Smith)
  - 15. Friends of the Museum - Portland
  - 16. Friends of the Museum
  - 1. Gande (Box 6)
  - 2. Ginpoh
  - 3. Ginpoh
  - 4. Gluck Auf
  - 5. Incoming Corr. H-N
  - 6. Lee Su Jan
  - 7. Mc
  - 8. McCoy, Georgia (Mrs. James C. Lowry)
  - 9. MACDONALD MINES
  - 10. Mauritz
  - 11. Memos (Mementos)
  - 1. Morand, Donald A. (Box 7)
  - 2. Music
  - 3. In. Corr. N-W
  - 4. Newspaper Cuttings
  - 5. Newspaper Cuttings
  - 6. Niemi
  - 7. Nolan, Bob
  - 8. Osland-Hill, Nora Waln
  - 9. Owens, 1960
  - 10. P-General
  - 11. Paquet
  - 12. Pending Business
  - 13. Political (Kennedy)
  - 14. Pope, Clifford
  - 15. Portland Zoo
  - 16. Price, Dolly
- Correspondence
  - R (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Receipts Personal (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hand-written receipts of Ruth Johnson Clarke (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Red China (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Reynolds (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Ritchic (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Ruth's Souvenirs (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - S (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Schools (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Secret Pal (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Shoemaker, Sam (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sokobin (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Stibolt (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - T (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Telephone #'s (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Tinkhams (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Unions (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - V (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - W (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Waldron (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Webster, Jerome (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Wentworth, Irwin (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - White, Henry & Esmee (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Winburn, Joan Stacy (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Winter berger (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - K.C. w u (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - y (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - yarnell (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - yuin (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Zell Bors. (Jade) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Zonta (Box 10, Folder 5)
- SERIES C
  - Correspondence - - Miscellancous unrecognized, to Ruth Johnson Clarke (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bill & Receipts of Ruth Johnson Clarke (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Business material of R. J. Clarke (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Ruth S. Clarke: Miscellancous (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - R. S. Clarke: misc. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Handpainted Chinese Country & Medical Scenes (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: RJC et al. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: RJC et al. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: RJC et al. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Bound newspaper clippings (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - loose newspaper clippings (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook - personal (marriage and honeymoon) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Photographs - personal (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - personal (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - scenic (some identified) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - collection notebook (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Photographs collection notebook (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - collection (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Photographs - collection negatives (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Artwork - cardboard-backed painting of mongate (Box 13, Folder 9)
- PAMPHLETS
  - Laufer, B.:The Chinese Imperial Gold Collection, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Jacobs, Leonebel: My China (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Yamanaka and Co.: Collection of Chinese and Other Far Eastern Art, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Metropolitan Opera House Spring The Royal Ballet, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - S.F. Opera House Stars of the Bolshoi Ballet, July 1968 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - The Royal Ballet Covent Garden (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Orientations, March 1973 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Orientations, April 1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Burt Brown Barker Memorial Message, (1873-1969) (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Laufer, B.: Insect Musicians and Cricket Champions of China (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Chinese and Siamese Art belonging to Miss Alice Boney, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Chung-Huan, W.: The King of Chinese Porcelain - The Ch'ai Yao Vase Tientsin, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Goddard, W.G.: Formosa Taipei, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Bensabott, R.: Chinese Jade and Other Semi-Precious Jewelry (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - The China Tiffin Club: Throughout the Years, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Gump, A. Livingston:Jade Hunt with inserts, circa 1931 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - The Altar of the Sacred Jade Pagoda San Francisco (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper clippings from Dad Johnson - Peotone and Chicago (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Small memorabilia (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Large memorabilia (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Genealogical material (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Business correspondence (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Letters of sympathy, (1963-5) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Zonta Club International (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Fashion show notes (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Miscellany (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Notebook - Quotations (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Notebook - Zonta, Dictionary Please, exhibits (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Notebook - Shai Art Club lecture (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Notebook - collection notes (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Notebook - trip (NY) with inserts, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Notebook - Sales record, clothing with inserts, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Notebook - nearly blank (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Book - The Little Oxford Dictionary, Geo. Ostler Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Book - The Three Weavers, Annie Fellows Johnston Boston: LC Page, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Book - New Testament Oxford Univ. Press (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Book - The Holy Bible, American Revision Committee NY: Thomas Nelson, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Book - Murray Warner MIT Class of '92 Special Printing, MIT Press, (1869-1920), 1929 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Book - The Conococheague Wilson College Annual vol. 17, Chambersburg, Pa., 1912 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - 1. Singer, Caroline and C. LeRoy Baldridge: Turn to the East Minton, Batch & Co.; New York, 1926; (autographed) (Box 16)
  - 2. Chinese Painting Assn. of Peking: The Shop Signs of Peking C.P.A. of Peking; Peking, 1931; (hand-painted illustrations)
  - 3. Parier, A. (?): Faits Mémorables des Emperevrs dela Chine Ponce graveur; Paris, (gravées par Helman.), undated; 40
  - 4. Doré, Henry S.J. (M. Kennelly, S.J. trans.) Researches into Chinese Super-Stitions T'usewei Printing Press; Shanghai, v. I + II, 1914
  - 5. Jl. of the China Branch of The Royal Asiatic Society v. 28 Theyü-li or Precious Records Transl. by Rev. geo. W. Clarke Kelly & Waish, Ltd.; Shanghai, 1893-1894
  - 6. Staunton, Sir george (Bart.) An Historical Account of the Embassy to the Emperor of China Printed for John Stockdale; Piccadilly, 1797
  - 7. Powers, Ella M. and Thoj. M. Balliet: The Silver-Burdett Readers. First Book, Silver Burdett & Co.; N.Y., 1906
  - 8. gordon, J. D.: Prayer Changes Things 11,000Th. South Africa general Mission - Marshall Bros.; Wimbledon, circa 1910?
  - 9. Burns, Robert: The Poetical works of... Collins' Clear-type Press; London, circa 1914?
  - 10. Holy Bible American Bible Society; N.Y., 1868; 12mo
  - 11. Alcott, L.M.: Eight Cousins or The Aunt-Hill Sampson Low, Marston & Co.; London, 1903?; 8vo
  - 12. Rollin, M.: The Ancient History of Egyptions,... V. II Chalmers, Ray & Co.; Dundee, 1804
  - 13. Anon.?: The Women who Followed the Lord S. W. Partriage & Co.; London, (inscribed to Mrs. C.-, 1901 1901
  - 14. Browning, Robert: Poems by E.B. Browning Thos. Y. Crowed & Co.; N.Y., (w/ gift card), 1856
  - 15. MacLaren, Ian: Beside The Bonnie Brier Bosh Dodd, mead & Co.; N.Y., 1895
  - 16. Fitgerald, Edward (trans.): The Rubaiyat of Omar Khaygam Collins'Clear-type Press; London, (Intro. by L.E. Housman)
  - 17. Ruskin, John: Sesame and Lilies Henry Altemus; Philadelphia, 1894
  - 18. Jims, Albert E. (Rev.): A Little Book of Comfort. geo. g. Harrap & Co. Ltd.; London, 1926
  - 19. The Indexed Testament London Bible Warehouse, 1902
  - 20. Woodbury, I.B.: The Anthem Thanksgiving F.J. Huntington; N.Y., circa 1874?
  - 21. Catholic Univ. of Peking Bulletin # 8, Dec-31
  - 22. Martin, W.A.P.: Hanlin Papers. Second Series Kelly & Walsh; Shanghai, 1894
  - 23. Russian ed. Holy Bible, 1920
  - 24. Hugo's Simplified System - Russian Reading Made Easy, post-1918
  - 25. Goodrich, Chauneey: a Pocket Dictionary - Chinese-English Peking, 1891
  - 26. Beuvin, Blanche Jacques: Verbes Irriguliers Français (Premier nulle) Lazarists of Pei-Jang; Peking, 1914
  - 27. Longfellow, H.W.: The Song of [UNK] Geo. of Harrap; London, circa 1925?; (imperfect copy)
  - 28. New Testament american Bible Society; N.Y., 1871
  - 29. The Union Hymn Book for Scholars (Sunday School Union) inscribed; lignes Lancaster, May 1867; (imperfect copy)
- Clarke II -, Notes, Scrapbooks, Photos
  - 1) Bridging the years - Shantung Mission, 1860-1937; (Green)
  - 2)-What one should know about Jade - Chinese Chronology
  - 3) Chinese Snuff Bottles
  - 4) The Pony Express
  - 5) Zell Bro's - Jade Scrapbook
  - 6) The Ceramic arts & Sculpture of China, (Red)
  - 7) Chinese Calligraphy & Painting
  - 8) New Terms for New Ideas
  - 9) Conococheague -, 1910; (leather bound)
  - 10) Lung - Wang - Tang - Guest Book - photos scrapbook, 1916 onward -
  - 11) (Translation & Explanation included) - Chinese Imperial Seal
  - 12) Blue Box - containing (mainly) photos
  - 13) British flat files, 5 - Scrapbook (red)
  - 14) British flat files, 6 - Journal (brown)
  - 15) Black Scrapbook - photos, clippings (concert) programs
  - 16) Brownish-Red scrapbook - photos, clippings & pamphlets of Chinese Art
  - 17) Green scrapbook - photos of China
- Clarke II -, Notebooks
  - 1) Yellow Envelope of loose photos - Chefoo School, 1915-25
  - 2) Green folder - Photos of Chefoo School Days
  - 3) Black - w/photos
  - 4) Green - w/photos
  - 5) Red-brown photos
  - 6) Red-brown photos
  - 7) Red-brown photos
  - 8) Blue - Men of Yale -, 1795-1966
  - 9) Gray - Scrapbook
  - 10) Red-Brown - photos scrapbook
  - 11) Blue - a Letter to the Witt Family
    Scope and Contents note
    - contains photo srapbook
  - 12) Black notebooks #1 - #8
    - contain postcards, programs etc.
- Photos (Box I)
  - 1) Blue Scrapbook-Eric & Clarke - contains photos
  - 2) Scrapbook - Peking, 1915; (Black)
  - 3) Photographs - scrapbook Changing Peking, Undated
  - 4) Scrapbook-No title & personal, no date -
  - 5) Black scrapbook - No title & no identification - personal photos & scenie Western tombs tour - photos
  - 6) Black photo scrapbook - no title
  - 7) Etching - Budana's Tower leans on emptiness
  - 8) Gray envelope w/photos & film roll
  - 9) Brown envelope - Photos from Milton wersch kul
  - 10) Photos in envelope from J. K. Gill
  - 11) White envelope - Leonibel Jacobs pictures Shanghai, Peking, China
  - 12) Brown Envelope - Complete set photographs
  - 13) [UNK] photos of tapestries & art typed descriptions
  - 14) Manila Envelope - Bill [UNK] - contains xeroxes of article
  - 15) Manila envelope - sent from Mrs. E. Clarke to Dr Hosmer Johnson - Gourd? collection detail
  - 16) Photos of Mrs. Clarke & her collection
  - 17) 2 large photos of chinese home?
  - 18) Gray Scrapbook no cover, photos
  - 19) Gray Scrapbook no cover, photos
  - 20) Gray Scrapbook with cover, photos
  - 21) Large Photo - Mrs. Clark (Ruth)
  - 22) Gray folder - contains stiff - backed photos
  - 1) greeting gray card from Major General & Mrs. Crozier Peking - also photos, 1932-33 -
  - 2) 5 pages w/mounted photos - boat cruise etc.
  - 3) Photo of - church members? - missionaries in white kobes
  - 4) Mounted photo - river & boat
  - 5) Large Photos - Clarkes & others
  - 6) - photo of homestead (Johnson) in Illinois
  - 7) Photo - Ruth Clarke w/ her collection
  - 8) Stiff page of photos (mounted) of China
  - 9) White photo folder - w/picture of R. Clarke & relatives
  - 10) Picture of Chinese Council, (9 men
  - 11) Photo - Dr. Johnson's Medical Students
  - 12) Photos - Ruth Johnson
  - 13) Photos - Ruth Johnson from Harris & Ewing - Wash DC
  - 14) Photos - Ruth Johnson from Geo. L. Wadds. Vancouver BC
  - 15) Photo - w. e. Neville (?) Maj. Gen. Comm. U.S. Marines
  - 16) Autographed Photo - Joe Brown -, 5/8/34
  - 17) Mounted photos - China
  - 18) Photo - Chinese School - Mrs. Charles F Johnson's pupils
  - 19) Wedding Photo